# 酱油汆儿 花椒油的酱油汆儿
Soy sauce, Soy sauce with Sichuan peppercorn oil
# 这叫一个地道
This is authentic
# 凉凉的 夏天来这么一碗
This dish is fresh, suitable for summer time.
# 水里搁点盐
Add some salt in the water
# 为了绿点 少点点油 来一点点
To give a green color, add a touch of oil
# 锅开了 烫香椿
The water starts boiling, Xiangchun (Chinese mahogany) in
# 这香椿必须要焯水
The Xiangchun (Chinese mahogany) must be blanched in the water
# 咱在北京讲究什么啊
What is the tradition in Beijing ?
# 夏天爱吃麻酱
In summer, our favorites' is sesame sauce!
# 焯完水了 关火
Finish blanching, turn off the fire
# 我就开始切黄瓜 黄瓜丝
I’m going to chop some shredded cucumber
# 原来胡同里头讲究吃这个
In the past, it was a traditional dish in Hutong.
# 这麻酱面的吃法太多了
There are so many ways to eat noodles with the sesame sauce
# 冰的凉凉的 酱油汆儿麻酱面
Cold and fresh, that’s the soy and sesame sauce noodles
# 天也热了来点这个 就两瓣蒜
Since the weather is getting hotter, let’s add 2 cloves of garlic
# 尤其那新蒜一下来 吃起来那美
specially with the fresh garlic, that tastes good
# 黄瓜丝 今天咱来个文吃的是吧
Shredded cucumber in the dish, so no meat today
# 有什么咱就搁什么就行了
Yeah, just cook whatever we have
# 香椿弄好了
Xiangchun (Chinese mahogany) done
# 切的稍微长点别太碎了
Chop it in long pieces, don't need to be too fine
# 吃的过瘾 有口感
The texture is better
# 香椿 小萝卜 很简单 黄瓜丝
Xiangchun (Chinese mahogany), reddish, Shredded cucumber, very easy
# 两边一切 人家还讲究
Cut in two, he’s very particular about chopping
# 我切的是眉毛葱 你看那小眉毛一弯
I chopped it like the eyebrow, take a look
# 白眉大侠 不是黑眉
Like kongfu master with white eyebrow
# 麻酱 二八酱
Sesame paste, made from 20% of sesame and 80% of peanut
# 加点盐
Add some salt
# 用水和用酱油和
Mix it with water and soy sauce
# 用水和 这是关键点
Mix with some water, that’s important
# 你像做其它的调味用麻酱的
If you make other recipes with sesame paste
# 比如说怪味 就用酱油和
For example the Guaiwei (a type of multi-flavor), mix the paste with soy sauce
# 你像北京的麻酱面 必须是水和
Or like the sesame paste noodles in Beijing, the paste has to be mixed with water
# 这麻酱还挺香
The sesame sauce smells good
# 好 咱这麻酱差不多了
Ok, almost done with the sesame sauce
# 一挑一条线 里边还挺稠
A little sticky, dripping like a string
# 再攉拢攉拢就开了 先搁一边
It’s OK now, put it aside
# 混合油
Mixed oil in
# 花生油
Peanut oil in
# 和香油
Sesame oil in
# 二伯给看着点锅
Er bai monitors the oil temperature
# 我这边看着这个油 下面喽
No problem, put the noodles in boiling water
# 炸炸花椒 你都下了吧
Fry some Sichuan peppercorn, all in
# 油温够高了 开始炸花椒油
It’s hot enough now, let’s make the peppercorn oil
# 花椒油 小点火
Turn down the fire
# 花椒油慢慢炸 小火沁一下
Make it slow, fry it slowly
# 这玩意必须得炸糊了
It has to be fried
# 不炸糊了不好吃了 也别太糊
It won’t be tasty if it’s not fried, don’t overcook anyway
# 说糊没糊 说没糊马上糊了
Really carefully with the timing
# 炸成褐色就行了 深褐色
Fry it till brown, dark brown
# 花椒捞不捞 花椒少留俩 嚼着香
Do we need to take the peppercorn out? Leave 2 inside, it’s good to chew it
# 行了小魏 不能再糊了
Take out now Xiaowei, it will be overcooked
# 再糊了就该苦了 好了 捞出来
It will be bitter if it’s overcooked, now take it out
# 葱丝姜丝 给它炝上
Shredded green onion and ginger, blanch them it the peppercorn oil
# 全加上 眉毛葱
Shredded green onion, all in
# 煸它一下 香味出来喽
fry them, the aroma is released
# 酱油一呲 就是酱油
Soy sauce in
# 汆儿齐了
Fry all the ingredients
# 小魏你怎么想起做一汆儿面
Xiaowei, why do you want to make this dish?
# 上次咱直播了一次
Last time, we were streaming
# 那网友都没看清楚 再做一遍
Our friends didn’t see clearly, so I want to do it again
# 二伯关火 我这儿照着呢
Er bai, turn off the fire. I am filming here.
# 你就看你那面吧
You just need to take care of the noodles
# 真香 全搁进去 地道啊
It smells so good, all in. Authentic
# 面条出锅 出锅喽
Take the noodles out
# 面条热气腾腾 行了 别太凉了
The noodles are still steaming, Ok don’t let it to be too cool.
# 你看它这个一搭 出盘仪式很重要
Look at that, the presentation is very important
# 有没有鲜花啊 鲜花没有有萝卜
Do we have some flowers? No, but we have some radish
# 搁这一堆 香椿搁到这儿
Put one accompaniment together, Xianchun put it here
# 好了 齐活
Well done !
# 酱油汆儿 花椒油的酱油汆儿
Soy sauce, Soy sauce with Sichuan peppercorn oil
# 让它好看点 齐活
Make it looks good, good job
# 麻酱 太有食欲了
Sesame sauce, make people want to try.
# 凉凉的 夏天来这么一碗
So fresh in summer days
# 还得搁两瓣蒜 齐了
And 2 cloves of garlic, finished
# 这叫一个地道
This is so authentic
# 大爷 我给您先来一口
Da Ye, let me serve you the first bite.
# 别来一口 你来一盆儿吧
Not just a bite, make it a bowl
# 来瓣蒜
Give me a clove of garlic
# 瞧大爷吃的 就是香
Look at Da Ye, it must be good
# 你看这声音 太棒了
And this sound, amazing
# 看你师父吃面什么水平
Let’s see your master's level of eating noodles
# 这味儿调的正合适 太好吃了
The season is correct, it’s amazing
# 花椒油的香味 麻酱的香味
There’s fragrance of peppercorn oil and sesame sauce
# 特别香 融为一体 太好吃了
it’s incredible, all fragrances merge together, so good
# 有网友问炒您糖色的时候
Some friends want to ask when you make the caramelized sugar
# 绵白糖 白砂糖和冰糖的区别都是什么
What’s the difference between soft white sugar, white granulated sugar and rock sugar
# 绵白糖你可以不加水
You don’t need to add water for soft white sugar
# 但是白砂糖冰糖必须是水油炒
But for the white granulated sugar and rock sugar, you has to fry them with oil and water
# 必须要加点水
you must add some water
# 绵白糖属于甜菜糖
Soft white sugar is made from sugar beet
# 砂糖和冰糖属于蔗糖
Granulated sugar and rock sugar are made from sugar cane
# 所以它那么大的糖块还有颗粒状
So they are granular sugar
# 你不加水的话它溶解的比较慢
They will melt slowly if you don’t add water
# 如果你火候再掌握的不当的话
And if you can’t control the temperature
# 会出现问题
There will be some problems
# 但是最主要的是冰糖
But the essential is by using the rock sugar
# 炒出来的糖色
The caramelized sugar
# 制出来的菜肴
And color of the dishes
# 红亮
will be shiny and bright.
# 糖色就跟红烧肉似的
It’s like making the red braised pork
# 冰糖出来就是亮
The rock sugar makes the color shiny
# 效果好
The result is better
# 好 下一个
OK next one